jobboard.io 2019-06-29

# Privacy - JobBoard.io

**Privacy Policy**[](https://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/validation?rid=41e27088-0d2f-43ee-a067-20acd2629a2d)

 _Effective Date: January 29, 2019_

The jobboard.io website is owned and operated by ZipRecruiter, Inc., a Delaware corporation.

This Privacy Policy provides information as to how ZipRecruiter, Inc. (“ _ZipRecruiter_ ,” “ _we_ ,” or “ _us_ “) collects and processes your Personal Data (defined below) through your use of the JobBoard.io website (“Website”), whether you are just a visitor to our Website or whether you use our Website as a customer.

It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specific occasions when we collect or process Personal Data about you (“ _Additional Privacy Notices_ ”) so that you are fully aware of how and why we are use your Personal Data. This Privacy Policy supplements the Additional Privacy Notices and is not intended to override them. In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Policy and Additional Privacy Notices, the express terms of Additional Privacy Notices will apply to the Personal Data to which they relate.

You may have different privacy rights under applicable laws depending on the country you are in when you visit or access our Website.

This Privacy Policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Alternatively, you can download a pdf version of the policy [_here_](https://d6dyoorq84mou.cloudfront.net/uploads/misc/jobboard.io+PRIVACY+POLICY+-+Effective+May+25%2C+2018.pdf) Please also use the Key Terms glossary in Section 1 below to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this Privacy Policy.

 **Click on the links below to jump to each section:**

  1. [Who we Are](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav1)
  2. [Key Terms](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav2)
  3. [Data We Collect About You](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav3)
  4. [How Data Is Collected](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav4)
  5. [How We Use Your Data](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav5)
  6. [Who We Share Your Data With](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav6)
  7. [Where your Data is Transferred](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav7)
  8. [How Long Your Data Will Be Kept](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav8)
  9. [Cookies and Tracking Technologies](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav9)
  10. [Data Security](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav10)
  11. [Your Data Subject Access Rights](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav11)
  12. [Links to Third Party Websites and Social Media Features](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav12)
  13. [California Privacy Rights](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav13)
  14. [Questions or Complaints](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav14)
  15. [Marketing](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav15)
  16. [Changes to This Privacy Policy](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav16)
  17. [Minors & Children](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav17)
  18. [How to Contact Us](https://www.jobboard.io/privacy-policy#nav18)

####  **1.  ** ** _WHO WE ARE_**

The Website is owned and operated by ZipRecruiter, Inc., a Delaware corporation (“ _ZipRecruiter_ ”).

ZipRecruiter Inc.  
604 Arizona Avenue, Santa Monica, California 90401, USA  
Delaware corporation (File Number 4829724)

Pursuant to Article 27 of Europe’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), we have appointed a representative in the UK to act as our GDPR Representative in the EU where required (“ _GDPR Representative_ ”). You can contact our GDPR Representative by sending an email to _[art27rep@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:art27rep@ziprecruiter.com)_ , or by writing to our GDPR Representative at:

ZipRecruiter UK Ltd.  
c/o Fieldfisher LLP  
Registered Office: Riverbank House, 2 Swan Lane, London, EC4R 3TT, UK  
ATTN: Privacy

For more information on the transfer of personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA), please see Section 7 below.

####  **2.  ** ** _KEY TERMS_**

It would be helpful to start by explaining some key terms used in this Privacy Policy:

The Ziprecruiter Group| This means ZipRecruiter Inc. and its wholly-owned subsidiaries, ZipRecruiter UK Ltd. and ZipRecruiter Israel Ltd.  
---|---  
Non-Personal Data| “Non-Personal Data” means data that is not considered Personal Data under applicable law. We reserve the right to treat data as Personal Data or Non-Personal Data based on the law applicable to the data and the data subject.  
Personal Data|  “Personal data” means any information or pieces of information that could identify you either directly (e.g., your name) or, where required by applicable law indirectly (e.g., through pseudonymised data, such as a unique ID number). This means that Personal Data includes things like email/home addresses, usernames, user generated content, financial information, and health information. It could also include certain Technical Data (defined below) such as unique numerical identifiers like your computer’s IP address or your mobile device’s MAC address, as well as cookies (“ _Device IDs_ ”), where required by applicable law  
Special Categories of Personal Data| This refers to sensitive Personal Data that reveals racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, philosophical beliefs or trade union membership; Genetic and biometric data; and Data concerning health, sex life or sexual orientation.  
Other Defined Terms| Capitalized terms have the definition where defined below.  
EEA| Refers to the European Economic Area.  
  
####  **3. _DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU_**

 ** _Personal Data_**

As permitted by applicable law in the country from which you access our Website and use our services, we may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of Personal Data about you. We have grouped these into the following categories of Personal Data:

  *  **“ _Identity Data_ ”** such as first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier.
  *  **“ _Contact Data_ ”** such as billing addresses, email addresses and telephone numbers.
  *  **“ _Financial Data_ ”** such as payment card details. However, please note that payment methods (e.g., credit card number and/or Paypal and/or bank account details) are not collected by us directly, but by secure payment service providers.
  *  **“ _Transaction Data_ ”** such as details about payments to and from you, and details regarding the services that you have subscribed to in relation to this Website.
  *  **“ _Technical Data_ ”** such as Device IDs, your login data, access dates and times, browser type and version, device information, cookie data, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access the Website.
  *  **“ _Profile Data_ ” **such as your username and password, orders made by you, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  *  **“ _Usage Data_ ”** such as information about how you use our Website, products and services.
  *  **“ _Marketing and Communications Data_ ” **such as your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third-parties and your communication preferences.

 ** _Non-Personal Data_**

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your Personal Data but is not considered Personal Data since it does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature.

 ** _If You Fail to Provide Personal Data Where Required to Provide Services to You_**

Where we need to collect Personal Data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, or a prospective contract, and you fail to provide that Personal Data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with our services). In this case, we may have to cancel the service you have with us (or requested from us), and you accept that as a condition of service.

 ** _Data That You Should Not Provide to Us_**

We do not require any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you. Accordingly, please do not provide this type of personal data to us.

 ** _ZipRecruiter as a Data Processor_**

ZipRecruiter acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. With respect to Personal Data provided by a client of ZipRecruiter to ZipRecruiter, we collect such information under the direction of that client and have no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Data we process. If you are a customer of such a ZipRecruiter client and would no longer like to be serviced by such client, please contact the client directly. If you seek access or want to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, you must direct such request to that client (the data controller). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by our service agreements with our clients.

We will retain Personal Data that we process on behalf of our clients for as long as needed to provide services to our client. ZipRecruiter will retain this Personal Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, and in accordance with our internal record keeping policies.

####  **4. _HOW DATA IS COLLECTED_**

We use different methods to collect Personal Data from and about you including, for example:

 ** _Direct Interaction_**

You may give us your identity, contact, billing and other information by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes Personal Data you provide when you:

  * sign-up for a free trial;
  * sign-up for a paid subscription;
  * create an account on our Website;
  * request information to be sent to you;
  * give us some feedback; or
  * otherwise submit Personal Data to us.

 ** _Automated Technologies or Interactions_** **.** As you interact with our Website, we may automatically collect Technical Data and Usage Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this Personal Data and Non-Personal Data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data and Usage Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies and other Tracking Technologies (defined below). For more information regarding our use of Tracking Technologies, please refer to “Cookies and Similar Technologies” below.

 ** _Third Parties_** **.** We may receive Personal Data in the form of Technical Data and Usage Data about you from various third-parties such as analytics providers or advertising networks.

####  **5. _HOW WE USE YOUR DATA_**

 ** _Non-Personal Data_**

Where permitted by applicable law, we may use your Non-Personal Data for any purpose not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy or any written representation we have made to you at the point and time of the data collection.

 ** _Personal Data_**

We will only use your Personal Data where permitted by i.e., when we have a business or commercial reason to use your personal data. For example:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into with you or have entered into with you
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation
  * Where you have given us your consent

 ** _Purposes for Which We Use Your Personal Data_**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of the ways we use your Personal Data, and the legal basis that we rely upon to do so; we will amend this table as required. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. We have also provided you with an explanation of some of the terms we use in this table:

  *  **‘Legitimate Interest’  ** means our interest in conducting and managing our business, to enable us to give you the best experience when using the Website, products, and services.  We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).
  *  **‘Performance of Contract’  ** means processing your Personal Data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.
  *  **‘Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation’  ** means processing your Personal Data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation to which we are subject.
  *  **‘Consent’ means that you consent to our use of your personal data for one or more specific purposes.  Where we rely on your consent to use your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. You can do this by contacting us at [dsars@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:dsars@ziprecruiter.com).  However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent.  If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.**

 **CONTEXT In which YOUR PERSONAL DATA is COLLECTED**|  **WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE MAY HOLD ABOUT YOU**|  **How we MAY use your personal data**|  **OUR LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA**  
---|---|---|---  
 **Account Creation**

When you create an account on our Website or sign up for a free trial or paid subscription

| · Identity

· Contact

· Billing

· Financial

· Technical

· Transaction

· Profile

· Other information you have shared with us about yourself (e.g. via your “My Account” page), by contacting us, or a question via the chat function

| · To process your order

· To enable you to receive our services

· To manage our relationship with you

· To manage payments, fees and charges. Please note that payment methods (e.g., credit card number and/or PayPal and/or bank account details) are not collected by us directly, but by secure payment service providers

· To collect monies owed to us

· To communicate with you regarding our services

| · To perform our contract with you so you can use our services

· For our legitimate interests to receive and/or recover monies owed to us, to operate our business, and to keep our records updated  
  
 **Website Administration**|  · Identity

· Contact

· Technical

| · To provide administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud

· To troubleshoot

· To perform data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data

· To run analytics or collect statistics

· To monitor and improve our website

| · For our legitimate interests to running our business

· To perform our contract with you and provide services to you  
  
 **Online Browsing** Where your Personal Data may be collected by cookies or similar technologies  
and data analytics| · Usage Data such as where you came from; login details; pages you looked at; duration of your visit; and/or specifics of the services you have selected

 **·** Technical Data such as your IP address; browser information; device information; and/or  
your unique ID and the expiration date of the ID

| · To improve our Website, products/services and your user experience

· To run analytics and collect statistics

· To enable our Website to function properly (ensure proper display of content); create and remember your account login details; interface personalization, such as language, or any user-interface customization (i.e. parameters attached to your device including your screen resolution or font preference), etc.

· Understand how you discovered our Website

| · For our legitimate interests to analyse and improve our Website and services; to improve your user experience; to better engage with you; and to keep our Website updated and relevant

· Consent, when required, to store cookies on your device  
  
 **Promotions**

Where we make suggestions and recommendations to you about products and/or services that may be of interest to you

| · Identity

· Contact

· Technical

· Usage

· Profile

| · To form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you to optimize your use of our services| · Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
 **Enquiries**  
Where your personal data is collected when you ask questions relating to our services and/or your account| · Identity  
· Contact  
· Other personal data you provide in relation to your enquiry  
· Content of chats, messages, or enquiries; number of messages you’ve sent and received; when you viewed a message; who responded to your chats| · Answer and manage your enquiries

· Run analytics and statistics

· Add your questions or concerns to your profile so we can understand your interests and preferences

· Troubleshoot any problems that you are experiencing

| · Performance of our contract with you

· Our legitimate interests: (i) to better engage with you; and (ii) to enter into a contract with you

· Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation (data subject access rights)  
  
####  **6. _WHO WE SHARE YOU DATA WITH_**

 ** _Personal Data_**

We may share Personal Data with the following parties:

 ** _Internal Parties_**

  * Companies within our corporate family that comprise the ZipRecruiter Group. **Access to your Personal Data will be controlled and only granted where necessary to provide our services to you and/or to allow us to perform any necessary or legitimate functions.**

 ** _External Third-Parties_**

  * Service providers that we use to support our business and help provide our services to you, including, but not limited to, third-parties that host our Website, assist us to verify your identity, perform website and platform maintenance, risk assessments, and security, perform data and web analytics, provide databases, IT services, customer service, payment platforms and credit card processing, communication services, and email services
  * We require all third-parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your Personal Data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions
  * Professional advisers such as lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance, financial, auditing, and accounting services to us so we can operate our business
  * Taxing authorities, such as the Internal Revenue Service and other authorities acting as processors based in the United States, the United Kingdom and other applicable countries, who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances
  * Fraud prevention and identity verification services where we believe that disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of ZipRecruiter, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with third-parties for the purposes of fraud detection and prevention, and credit risk reduction
  * In connection with or during negotiations of any proposed or actual financing, merger, purchase, sale, sale or transfer of some or all of our assets or stock, joint venture, or any other type of financing, acquisition or business combination of our company(ies), or all or any portion of our assets, or transfer of all or a portion of our business to another company, including without limitation in the event of a divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other event, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding. In the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets or stock, Personal Data that we hold about our clients and users of our services will be one of the assets that will be transferred. If a change happens to our business, the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy
  * Other third-parties where you have expressly consented to the disclosure of your Personal Data
  * Law enforcement agencies, courts, supervisory authorities, regulatory bodies and certain other third-parties, to the extent that we are permitted or required to do so by law, or in order to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, or in the interests of national security, or to respond to verified requests relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity
  * To enforce our [Terms of Use](https://www.ziprecruiter.com/terms) and other agreements with you, to respond to, and defend ourselves against, claims asserted against us, to protect the rights, property, or safety of ZipRecruiter, our services, customers or others, or to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities.

 ** _Non-Personal Data_**

Where permitted by applicable law, we may share your Non-Personal Data for any purpose not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy or any written representation we have made to you at the point and time of the data collection.

####  **7. _WHERE YOUR DATA IS TRANSFERRED_**

ZipRecruiter Inc. is headquartered in the United States of America (USA).  The information that you provide or that we collect as a result of your interaction with the Website and/or your use of our services on the Website is transferred to the USA and/or to another country where we have a subsidiary or where we have engaged service providers. Some countries that are not located within the EU may be recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection.  For transfers from the EU to countries not considered as adequate by the European Commission, we have put in place measures, including by ensuring that the recipient is bound by EU Standard Contractual Clauses, to protect your Personal Data. When we transfer Personal Data from the EU or Switzerland to the USA, we also rely on the EU-U.S. or Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks (“Privacy Shield”), and in making such transfers, we adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles, as described in our Privacy Shield certification.

We are committed to upholding the Privacy Shield Principles.

To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. [[https://www.privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)]

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, we are subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [[https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint)], you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

####  **8. _HOW LONG YOUR DATA WILL BE KEPT_**

We will not retain your Personal Data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of Personal Data and in determining the appropriate retention period, we consider several criteria, including, but not limited to, the purpose for which we hold your Personal Data, our legal, accounting, reporting and/or regulatory obligations in relation to that Personal Data, e.g., financial or tax reporting obligations, whether our relationship with you is ongoing, e.g., where you use more than one of our products and/or services, any specific request you may have made in relation to the deletion of your Personal Data, or where we have a legitimate interest in relation to the management of our own rights, e.g., the defence of any claims. In some circumstances we may anonymize your Personal Data so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case we may use such information without further notice to you. Once you no longer have a relationship with us, we will retain and securely destroy your Personal Data subject to the foregoing and in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. If you request to receive no further contact from us, we will keep some basic information about you on our suppression list in order to avoid sending you unwanted materials in the future.

#### 9\. _COOKIES & TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES_

ZipRecruiter and third parties may use cookies or other tracking technologies (e.g., pixels, beacons, scripts, etc.) (“ _Tracking Technologies_ ”) in connection with the Website to collect information about interactions with the Website. For more information about the types of cookies and Tracking Technologies that we, and certain third parties use, and why we use them, and how you can control these, please review our policy regarding [**_Cookie Policy_**](https://www.jobboard.io/cookie-policy/).

If you are accessing the Website from other than the EEA, you understand that we apply U.S. law and the U.S. advertising industry self-regulatory program to Tracking Technologies associated with the Website.

#### 10\. _DATA SECURITY_

We use appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect Personal Data we process about you.

However, no transmission of information via the Internet or wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Data, you acknowledge that there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control and accordingly, the security, integrity and privacy of data exchanged between you and us through the Website cannot be guaranteed.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected Personal Data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

The safety and security of your Personal Data also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your login or account credentials with anyone and keep your account information secure. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Website like message boards, where information will be available to other users of the Website. If you believe that your access credentials or Personal Data have been compromised, please contact us immediately.

####  **11. _YOUR DATA SUBJECT ACCESS RIGHTS (_ _for data subjects in the EEA)_**

Data subjects in the EEA have the following rights with respect to their Personal Data:

 **YOUR RIGHTS**|  **WHAT CAN YOU REQUEST**  
---|---  
Right to **Information**|  The right to know what Personal Data we hold about you and how we use it.  
Right to **Access**|  The right to be provided with a copy of your Personal Data (subject to certain restrictions).  
Right of **Rectification**|  The right to require us to correct any incomplete or inaccurate Personal Data we hold about you, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us. If you have a user account with us, you also have the option of correcting your information directly in your account.  
Right **to erasure/be forgotten**|  This enables you to ask us to delete or remove Personal Data where there is no good reason for us to continue to process it. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request for erasure and in such circumstances, will notify our reasons to you.  
Right to **restrict processing**|  The right to require us to restrict processing of your Personal Data, i.e., you can request that we suspend the processing of your Personal Data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.  
Right to request **data portability**|  In certain circumstances, you have the right to request the transfer of your Personal Data to you or to a third party in a commonly used machine-readable format. Note, however, that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.  
Right to **object to processing**|  You have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Data in the following circumstances: (i) at any time to your Personal Data being processed for direct marketing (including profiling); or (ii) in certain other situations, to our continued processing of your Personal Data, e.g., our processing of your Personal Data when such processing is based on our legitimate interests. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.  
Right **to withdraw consent at any time**|  You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your Personal Data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.  
Right **not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated decision-making**|  The right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing (including profiling) that produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you. However, your right does not apply if: (i) you gave us your explicit consent to use your personal data to make our decision; (ii) we are allowed by law to make our decision; or (iii) our automated decision was necessary to enable us to enter into a contract with you.  
  
 ** _Method for Requesting Information Pursuant to Your Rights_**

If you would like to exercise any of the data subject access rights in the table above (each, an “ _Access Request_ ”) please send an email to [dsars@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:dsars@ziprecruiter.com) and we will send you a Data Subject Access Request Form.

 ** _No Fee Usually Required_**

You will not usually be required to pay a fee to access your Personal Data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

 ** _What We May Need from You_**

Once we receive your Access Request, we may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your Personal Data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that Personal Data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.

If we are not clear as to what you are requesting, we may also need to contact you for clarification so we can more fully respond to your request.   

If we cannot locate any records about you, we may also ask you for additional information to assist us in locating records, if they exist.

 ** _Time Limit to Respond_**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

#### 12\. _LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES AND SOCIAL MEDIA FEATURES_

Our Website may from time to time, contain links to third-party services such as websites, locations, platforms, applications or services operated by third parties. If you follow a link to or otherwise access any of these third-party services, these third-party services may use their own cookies, web beacons, and other Tracking Technology to independently collect information about you and may solicit Personal Data from you. Please note that these third-party services have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these parties’ policies or practices. Please check these policies before you share any Personal Data with these third-party services.

We may offer you the opportunity to use your social media login when interacting with our Website. If you do so, please be aware that you may be sharing your profile information with us. The personal data that is shared will depend on your social media platform settings. Please visit the relevant social media platform and review its privacy policy to understand how your personal data is shared and used in this context.

Social media features may also collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie or other Tracking Technologies to enable the applicable social media feature to function properly. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing such features.

The Website may include tools provided by us or third-party services that enable you to send a message to another person. If you use any such tools, please ensure that you only send messages to persons to whom you have permission to send messages. Absent the recipient’s consent, we will only use their Personal Data that you provide us to facilitate such messages.

#### 13.  _CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS_

California residents have the right to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information (as defined by the California Shine the Light Act) to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless we provide them with an ability to exercise choice regarding such disclosures. We comply with this law by providing California residents with the ability to opt-out of, or prospectively withdraw their consent, if they have previously opted-in to, the disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident, to receive confirmation of how we comply with this law, or to make a request or to opt out at any time, please contact us [privacy@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:privacy@ziprecruiter.com) or mail us at the address provided in Section 17 below. Any request must include _“California Privacy Rights Request_ ” in the first line of the description and must include the requestor’s name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code.

#### 14.  _QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS_

 ** _Data Subjects Located Outside the European Economic Area and Switzerland_**

If you have a complaint, or if you have any questions or requests regarding your Personal Data, please email us at [dsars@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:dsars@ziprecruiter.com), and specify the country in which you are located.  

 ** _Data Subjects Located within the European Economic Area & Switzerland_**

If you have a complaint, or if you have questions or requests regarding your Personal Data, please email us at [dsars@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:dsars@ziprecruiter.com), and specify the country in which you are located.  If we are not able to address your concern and you are a resident of the EU, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Authority where you are located or where the issue took place. For contact details of your local Data Protection Authority, please see [www.ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm](http://www.ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).  Contact information for the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), which is the supervisory authority in the UK can be found at [https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint).

#### 15.  _MARKETING_

We may use your Personal Data to send you information about the services provided by the ZipRecruiter Group; provided, however that we will obtain consent to do so from EEA data subjects. You may unsubscribe from our marketing e-mails by clicking “Unsubscribe” in any promotional e-mail communications we send you. As permitted by applicable law, you cannot opt-out of non-marketing, services-related notices.

#### 16.  _CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY_

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time.  If we propose to make any material changes, we will notify you by posting a notice on the Website or by issuing an email to the email address listed by registered users prior to the changes becoming effective.  You acknowledge that it is your responsibility to maintain a valid email address as a registered user, and to review the Website and this Privacy Policy periodically in order to be aware of any modifications. If you object to any changes to the revised Privacy Policy, you can stop using our services and close your account with us.  However, if you continue to use our services (including the Website) after we publish a new or updated Privacy Policy, you acknowledge that such continued use means that the treatment of your Personal Data will be subject to the new or updated Privacy Policy.

#### 17.  _MINORS & CHILDREN_

Our Services and the Website are not intended for use by persons under the age of 18 years. ZipRecruiter does not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Data from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register to use our Website. In the event that we learn that we have collected Personal Data of a child under the age of 13, we will delete that data to the extent required by applicable law as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any Personal Data from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:privacy@ziprecruiter.com).

#### 18\. _HOW TO CONTACT US_

 **T** **echnical or Customer Service Questions**.  Wherever you are located, if you have any questions about your account, and/or technical or other customer support questions about your use of our services, please contact us by using the communication means described below.

 **Type of Enquiry**|  **Contact**|  **Email address**|  **Mailing Address**|  **Telephone**|  **LIVE CHAT**  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
Technical Support| Customer Service| [support@jobboard.io](mailto:support@)| See Below| 1-843-580-3860

(9am – 9pm EST)

| Via Website  
General Customer Service Enquiries| Customer Service| [support@jobboard.io](mailto:support@jobboard.io)| See Below| 1-843-580-3860

(9am – 9pm EST)

| Via Website  
  
 ** _Data Privacy Questions._** If you have any questions regarding our personal data practices, please contact us by using the communication means described below.

Data Subject Access Rights| Data Privacy Representative| [dsars@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:dsars@ziprecruiter.com)| See Below| Request by Mail or Email| Send Request by Mail or Email  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
General Privacy-Related Questions| Data Privacy Representative| [privacy@ziprecruiter.com](mailto:privacy@ziprecruiter.com)| See Below| Request by Mail or Email| Send Request by Mail or Email  
  
 ** _Mailing Addresses_**

U.S. Mailing Address| U.K. Mailing Address  
---|---  
ZipRecruiter, Inc.  
Attn: Business Affairs  
604 Arizona Avenue,  
Santa Monica, CA 90401, USA

Delaware Corporation  
File Number: 4829724  
ICO Registration Number: ZA454860

| ZipRecruiter UK Ltd.  
C/o Fieldfisher LLP  
Riverbank House, 2 Swan Lane, London, EC4R, England, UK  
Company No. 9988220  
ICO Registration Number: ZA197224

 **Article 27 Representative**  
ZipRecruiter UK Ltd.  
C/o Fieldfisher LLP  
Attn: Privacy  
Riverbank House, 2 Swan Lane, London, EC4R, England, UK  
Email: art27rep@ziprecruiter.com
